-=cece&飞飞字幕组=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
--------------------------
cece&飞飞字幕组，只致力于做最好的字幕
-=cece&飞飞字幕组=-
制作: 飞飞
校对: 西西
组长：cece
-==组员：cece&飞飞==-
老爸老妈浪漫史 第一季 第十六集
How.I.Met.Your.Mother
Season 01 Episode 16
孩子们，说到爱情
kids,when it comes to love,
最好的一对是顺其自然的一对
the best relationships are the ones
that just come naturally.
独立完成的作品
My first solo batch.
嗯，我觉得还应该烤久一点
En,I think those need to stay in the
oven a while longer.
给你一条专业建议
Here's a professional tip.
还是液状的，这可不是纸托蛋糕
If it's still runny,it's not a cupcake.
这是种饮料
It's a beverage.
哦，好的，和Victoria在一起的时光是快乐的……
Yeah,well,Things with Victoria were fun,
轻松的……
and easy,
也是毫不繁复的
and uncomplicated.
非常甜蜜
It was pretty great.
你在涂你的屁股？
are you coloring in your butt?
我有个重要的面试
I have a big interview coming up,
但我的西裤上有个破洞
and my suit has holes in it.
我不会缝纫，也没有一条海军蓝内裤
所以……
I can't sew,I don't own navy boxers,so,yeah
我只好涂我的屁股
I'm coloring in my butt.
那就穿条别的西裤
So wear another one.
我没有另一条了
I don't have another one.
我穷死了
I'm flat broke.
我剩下的选择就只有运动服和光屁股了
（英语中suit指西服，但tracksuit指运动装
birthday suit指裸体）
My only other suit options are track or birthday.
伙计，你要穿着这个去面试
Dude,you show up to an interview in that,
即使是Granola公司招收素食主义嬉皮士律师
（职业嬉皮原则上是素食主义者）
even the hippie lawyers from Granola
Mountain Earth Pals
也会直接把你炒鱿鱼的
will hackey sack you straight out the door.
好吧，是国家资源保护委员会
Okay,it's the National Resource Defense Council,
是我梦想中的职业
and it's my dream job.
不过还只是实习而已
Except it's only an internship,
没有工资的
and I won't be getting paid.
大部分时间就是给人倒咖啡
Mostly getting people coffee.
但那些我送咖啡的人
But the people I'm getting coffee for
他们的老板正在拯救世界
their bosses are going to save the world.
好吧，明天……
Okay,tomorrow......
我先告诉你这将震动你的世界
and I should mention this is gonna
rock your world
明天我带你去见我的私人裁缝
tomorrow I'm taking you to my personal tailor.
裁缝？
A tailor?
Barney，我每周赚负300美元
Barney,I make negative $300 a week,
而且我要省下这些负收入准备我的婚事
and I need every negative penny of
that for my wedding.
放心，那个人只收三分之一的费用
Relax,my guy does everything for
one-third the cost.
而且你也不可能穿着这个“反讽双引号”的“西服”去结婚
And there is no way you're getting married in that sarcastic- quotation-marks "suit."
明天，中午，我的裁缝
Tomorrow,noon,my tailor.
谢谢不用了，伙计
No thanks,dude.
-中午？
-中午
-Noon?
-Noon.
-好吧
-到时候见
-Okay.
-See you then.
嘿，姑娘们
Hey,girls.
我正要去见Ted
I'm on my way to meet Ted.
是我们两个月纪念日
It's our two-month-iversary,
所以我们要共进晚餐
so we're going out to dinner.
棒极了！你回答了我所有要问的问题
Great!that answers all the questions I didn't ask.
Robin！
Robin!
哦，得了吧
Oh,come on.
我们相互拆台
We bust on each other.
正说明我们有着亲密的友谊
We're just at that place in our strong friendship.
真的？
Really?
别碰我
Get off me.
哦，看见没有？我又这么做了
Oh,see? I did it again.
你们在干什么？
what are you guys up to?
哦，挑婚纱
Oh,dress shopping.
我给很多婚纱店做过蛋糕
You know,I make wedding cakes for
a lot of fancy bridal shops.
你愿意的话，我可以带你去啊
If you want,I could take you shopping,
也许还有优惠
maybe get you a discount.
真的？那太好了
Really? That'd be great.
我该接这个
I should take this.
喂
Hello.
嘿，我以为明天就我们两个人呢
Hey,I thought it was going to be just us tomorrow.
怎么又邀请Punky Brewster了？
（Punky Brewster是一情景喜剧女主人翁）
What's with inviting Punky Brewster?
Robin，你应该想开些
Ted和Victoria在一起了
Robin,you've gotto get over this Ted and Victoria thing.
你本可以有机会的,但现在他已经向前看了
You had your chance,and now he's moved on.
你就不能为他们感到高兴吗？
Can't you just be happy for them?
我最多只能回应你一个假微笑和一双死鱼眼
The best I can give you is a fake smile and dead eyes.
接受
Sold.
Victoria，怎么了？
Victoria,what's wrong?
我刚收到来自一家烹饪学会的奖学金邀请
I've just been offered a fellowship at
a culinary institute
……在德国
......in Germany.
等等，德国，欧洲？
Wait. Germany,Europe?
要去两年
It's for two years.
我原意为我的机会不大
I figured I didn't have much of a chance,
因为他们通常不招收美国人，但……
cause they don't let many Americans in,but...
我录取了
I'm in.
嗯，是那个欧洲的德国？
So,this is the Europe Germany?
还会有哪个德国？
What other Germany would it be?
Epcot里面那个？
（迪士尼公园的Epcot分园
有各国民俗风景区）
The one in Epcot?
Ted
Ted.
对不起
sorry
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还不确定要不要去
I don't know if I'm going to go.
而且如果你去了的话我们这又算什么？
And if-if you do,what does that mean for us?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是……
I just......
我不认为异地恋会有好的结果
I don't think that long distance really
works for anyone.
哦，天啊，当然了
Oh,god,no.
异地恋是高中生在上大学前为了上床而讲的骗话
Long-distance is a lie teenagers tell each other to get laid the summer before college.
所以，我们选择只有……
So,that leaves us with...
要么你留在这儿
either you stay here,
要么我们分手
or we break up.
听着，我们顺其自然好么
look,let's just see how things progress,
如果到9月份，我们对彼此还有……
and if by September,we still feel...
我周一就要离开了
I have to leave on Monday
9月份第几个周一？
Monday,September the...?
Ted
Ted.
你有什么看法？
Do you have any thoughts?
真希望我们能有多点时间思考我们真正要什么
Maybe we should each take some time to think about what we want.
我们明天再见面讨论吧
We'll meet up tomorrow to discuss it.
就这么定了
It's a date.
而从这里，事情开始一发不可收拾
And that's when things got complicated.
嘿，宝贝，婚纱店怎么样？
Hey,baby,how's the dress place?
这里一切都是蓬蓬的，白白的
Everything's so fluffy and white.
好像在一团棉花糖里买东西一样
It's like shopping in a marshmallow.
Barney的裁缝怎么样？
How's Barney's tailor?
这里的一切都暗暗的，乱糟糟的,看起来好像非法的
everything here is dark and sketchy
and seems illegal.
好像在Barney的脑子里买东西一样
It's like shopping in Barney's mind.
-祝你好运，宝贝
-再见
-good luck,baby.
-Bye.
嘿，Barney
Hey,Barney,
我心里有点发怵
I'm not sure about this.
住在宠物店后面的裁缝？
A tailor in the back room of a pet store?
听着，你还想不想要一套好西装另附送一只兔子了？
Look,do you want a quality suit and
a free rabbit or not?
Ted，Sergei说别在这儿唉声叹气了
Ted,Sergei says stop moping around.
你打扰到他工作了
You're distracting him from his process.
你会说乌克兰语？
You speak ukrainian?
伙计们，我现在进退两难了
Guys,I'm kind of screwed here.
我不想失去Victoria
I don't want to lose Victoria,
但我也不想只因为我让她留下
but I can't ask her to stay just for me.
而且又不可能异地恋
And long distance definitely isn't an option.
不，不，不可能
No. No,no,no. No way.
你知道谁喜欢异地恋吗？
You know who likes long distance?
女孩儿们，只有聊天没有性生活
Girls. It's all talking and no sex.
杀了我吧
Kill me now.
别诋毁异地恋
Don't knock long-distance relationships.
我认为是可行的
I really think they can work.
真的？你？
Really? You?
那当然
Absolutely.
我现处于四段异地恋中
I'm juggling four right now.
马德里的Lisa
There's lisa in Madrid,
东京的Erica
there's Erica in Tokyo,
丹麦的Laura
there's Laura in Denmark,
还有34号大街的Kelly
and Kelly on 34th street.
最后那个以为我是基尔拉尼的牧羊人
The lass thinks I'm a humble sheep
shearer from Killarney.
Ted，你还记得大学时候Lily到巴黎去进修暑假艺术课程
Ted,do you remember in college when Lily
did that summer art program in Paris?
她一直提起一个法国男生，Gabriel
she kept talking about this cheesy French guy,Gabriel.
于是我就到那边去了
So,I went out to visit,
正好有个派对
and there was this party.
那个Gabriel也去了
And who shows up but Gabriel.
他留着两撇俗气的法国小胡子
And he's got this weak-ass,thin French moustache.
我不是惹事生非的人
Yet I'm not much of a fighter,
但我知道我能搞定这个小怪胎
but I knew I could take this weird little dude.
所以我把他叫到一边
So,I took him aside,
保持沉默
and I got all creepy quiet,
杀人的眼神
I got the crazy eyes going,
然后我说
and I said,
你离Lily远点儿
"you stay away from Lily,
否则我就把你的胡子从你恶心的法国脸上咬下来
or I swear to god I'll eat that moustache
right off of your ugly French face."
是的，然后他逃跑了
Yeah,then he literally ran away.
我想他哭了
I think he was crying.
我从来没有告诉Lily
I never told Lily about it.
说实话，我不为此感到骄傲
To be honest,I'm not very proud of it.
说真正的实话，我很骄傲
To be even more honest,I am.
除了向欧洲人展示美国人的一贯风貌以外
other than confirming a lot of European
stereotypes about Americans,
这个故事还有什么意义吗？
did that little story have a point?
是的，意义就是，尽管Lily是我终生心灵伴侣
Yeah,the point is that even though Lily
is my soul mate,
异地恋几乎断送了我们
long distance still almost killed us.
如果你认为有可能
Victoria就是那一半的话
If you think that there's any chance
that Victoria is your soul mate,
你应该让她留下
you should ask her to stay.
但是，我就是不知道，一切都太早了
But,I don't know if she is. It's still so early,
不过，她有可能就是啊
but yeah,she could be.
哦，得了吧，你都不了解她
Oh,please.You barely know this girl.
她最喜欢的颜色是什么？
What's her favorite color?
她喜欢猫还是喜欢狗？
Is she a cat person or a dog person?
她乐不乐意三人行？
Is she open to a three-way?
Ted，我买部手机做的研究都比你足
Ted,I do more research than this before
buying a cell phone.
另外仅供参考，我的手机支持“三方通话”
And FYI,yes,I have three-way calling.
听着，她不可能喜欢猫
Look,she can't be a cat person.
我是喜欢狗的人,爱狗者物以类聚
I'm a dog person,I'm attracted
to other dog people.
你确定？
Are you sure?
喂
hello.
嘿，随机问题
Hey,random question.
你喜欢猫吗？
How do you feel about cats?
猫？
Cats.
讨厌那部歌剧，喜欢那种动物
（一著名歌剧名为《猫》）
Hated the musical,love the animal.
了解
Good to know.
好的
okay.
再见
Good-bye.
她喜欢猫
She's a cat person.
我根本不了解这女孩儿
I don't know this girl at all.
棒极了
excellent.
我们选这个
We'll take this one.
这是我的西装不该由我来选吗？
it's my suit.Shouldn't I be the one to choose?
乖，给你个针垫玩儿
here. Play with this pin cushion.
上帝啊
God.
我看起来帅呆了
I'm going to look hot.
Marshall，我可不能让你穿着这样的行头去打败仗
Marshall,I can't let you waste a suit this
nice fighting a losing battle
就什么狗屁资源保护
for our planet's survival.
这是强者的西装
This is a suit for winners.
我给你安排个面试,到我们公司来
I am getting you an interview at my office.
我们的法律分部需要像你这样优秀的人才
We need good men like you in our legal department.
我们经常吃官司
We get sued a lot.
不行
No way.
我不卖第二家
The kid does not sell out.
来嘛，伙计
come on,dude!
三个月跟我工作
Three months working with me,
比Lily一年赚的还多
you'll make more than Lily makes in a year.
不
No.
我意已决
I've made my decision.
我也是
So have I.
如果我要求一个女生为了我而放弃梦想
If I ask this girl to give up her dreams for me,
如果两个星期后我们又没能在一起
and two weeks later,it's not working out,
我不是成了一个大混球了吗？
I'm,like,the biggest jerk of all time.
只能说这对一段刚起步的恋情而言太过强求了
It's just too much pressure on a new relationship.
我会让她走的
I'm going to tell her to go.
于是我那天晚上与她见面并告诉她我的决定
And so I met her that night to
tell her my decision.
好吧，我考虑了很久……
All right,I've been thinking a lot about this...
嗯，在你说出来之前
okay,before you say anything,
我先给你这个
I wanted to give you this.
这个才是……
This is what happens when you,
烤熟的成品
you know,let them finish baking.
我想要你留下来
I want you to stay.
这里的一切都暗暗的，乱糟糟的,看起来好像非法的
Everything here is darkand sketchy,
and seems illegal.
好像在Barney的脑子里买东西一样
It's like shopping in Barney's mind.
-祝你好运，宝贝
-再见
-good luck,baby.
-Bye.
那么，你想要件什么样式的？
Now,what sort of dress did you have in mind,dear?
不要太雍容或者太华丽
Nothing too huge or-or poofy.
我不是很爱花俏
I'm not really a girlie girl.
不过我还是希望能象个漂亮的公主
But I would like to look like a
beautiful princess.
我看见店前面有几套不错的
I saw a couple up front that were nice.
橱窗里的？
By the window?
恕我冒犯，亲爱的
No offense,dear,
那些都在你能承受的范围之外
but those are a little out of your price range.
她这话从哪儿来？
Where does she get off?
她又不知道我的收入是多少
She doesn't know how much money I make.
哦，这些女人都是行家
Oh,these women are experts.
她们看看你的内衣就可以知道你的年收入是多少
They can guess your net annual income just
by looking at your underwear.
该死的老式海军短裤和廉价三点式
Damn you,old navy and your reasonably-priced
three-packs!
至少我们有免费的香槟！
At least we get free champagne!
还有蛋糕
And cake.
说起来，Victoria
Speaking of which,Victoria,
关于甜甜圈奖学金的问题,你考虑好了没有？
have you decided what to do about your doughnut fellowship?
嗯，我也不清楚
You know,I don't know.
我是说，我是想去
I mean,I want to go,
但我也不想失去Ted
but I don't want to lose Ted.
我想过异地恋的可能
I even thought about long distance,
如果能行的话
as if that ever works.
光聊天没性生活？杀了我吧
All talking and no sex.Kill me now.
我知道这听起来也许比较土
I know it sounds lame,
但我想Ted有可能就是我的真命天子
but I actually think that Ted might be the one.
很难说离开就离开
That's pretty hard to walk away from.
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得要是为了爱情拒绝事业就有点像《复制娇妻》了
I'd feel a little stepford turning down
a huge opportunity
就为了和一个刚认识没两个月的男人
to chase some guy I'd only known two months.
但这不是随便哪个男的
But this isn't just some guy.
这可是Ted
This is Ted.
他棒极了
He's amazing.
他是我认识的最好的男人
He's the best guy I know.
美国最好的，但是德国男人？
in America,but German guys?
我愿意让他们每天给我的干果片撒上面包屑
I would let them bread my schnitz any day,
明白我的意思吗？
if you know what I mean.
-说实话，不是很明白
-性爱
-I really don't...
-sex.
对不起，女士
Excuse me,ma'am.
这瓶搞定了
This bastard's kicked.
谢谢
Thanks.
没关系，伙计们,我讨厌这套
It's okay,guys,I hate it.
-糟糕透了
-很丑，真的很丑
-Just horrible.
-It's bad,it's really bad.
前短，后长？
Short in front,long in the back?
这是婚纱中的Mullet
（一种发型，前短后长）
That is the Mullet of wedding dresses.
要知道，Victoria，Marshall和我曾经有过异地恋
You know,Victoria,Marshall and I did long distance once.
大学的时候，我到巴黎去进修
In college,I did an art course in Paris.
我是那儿唯一的美国人
I was the only American there.
非常的孤单
It was really lonely.
我只有一个朋友，Gabrielle
I only had one friend,Gabrielle.
她长得有点怪
She was kind of homely and strange-looking,
她还很在意她嘴唇上的两撇小胡子
and she was really self-conscious about
this little moustache she had.
后来，学期刚过一半的时候
Anyway,halfway through the semester,
她忽然不理我了
she just stopped talking to me,
我一直没弄明白为什么
and I never figured out why.
然后我又成孤单一人了
And then I had nobody.
唯一让我坚持过来的信念是
The only thing that got me through was knowing that
我的心灵伴侣还在家乡等我回去
my soul mate was back at home waiting for me.
如果Ted是你的心灵伴侣
If Ted's your soul mate,
也许这就值得你留下
then it may be worth it to hang onto him.
但我如何才能知道他是不是呢？
But how am I supposed to know if we're soul mates?
这一切都太早了
It's too soon.
说曹操，曹操到
Speak of the devil.
喂
Hello.
嘿，随机问题：你喜欢猫吗？
Hey,random question: How do you feel cats?
猫，讨厌歌剧，喜欢动物
Cats. Hated the musical,love the animal.
喜欢猫的人
A cat person.
真是不出意料啊
Why am I not surprised?
拜
Bye.
为什么Ted想知道我喜不喜欢猫？
Why does Ted want to know if I like cats?
也许他想送你一只
Maybe he's going buy you one.
我的确听到电话里有狗叫声
I did hear barking in the background.
也许他正在一家宠物店里
Maybe he was in a pet store.
他想让我们一起养只猫吗？
Does he want us to get a cat together?
也许他想用可爱的猫咪引诱你留下
Maybe he's using an adorable kitty to guilt you into staying.
这招很低劣
that is low.
你真这么认为？
Do you really think that's what he's doing?
我都不会等等看是不是真的
I wouldn't even wait to find out.
我立马坐下一班飞机去德国
I would be on the next plane to Germany.
哦，天啊，你们真不会撒谎
Oh,god,you guys are sucky liars.
-丑死了，丑死了
-我无语了
-Ugly,ugly,ugly.
-I don't know what to say.
知道吗
You know what?
我们不敢这么找
We're doing this all wrong.
我去帮你那件橱窗里的婚纱，就试穿而已
I am going to get you one of those
front window dresses,just for fun.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我很好
I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
只是看起来你恨不得马上让Victoria出国去
Just kind of seemed like you're trying to
hustle Victoria out of the country.
没有啊，我只是在支持她
I'm not,I'm just trying to support her.
她获得了一个超级重要的甜点奖学金
She got a super-important dessert scholarship.
别说得这么讽刺
stop being sarcastic.
那本就是个超级重要的甜点奖学金
It is a super-important dessert scholarship.
谁说出口都显得讽刺
that's hard to say without sounding sarcastic.
听着……
Look...
我知道你不怎么喜欢Victoria
I know you're not Victoria's biggest fan,
但Ted和她在一起很开心
but she seems to make Ted happy.
所以在你用自己的航空附赠里程为她买机票前好好想想吧
So think about that before you use your
miles to buy her a plane ticket.
有人想当“漂亮公主”
Somebody say "beautiful princess."
哦，我的天啊，太完美了
Oh,my gosh,it's perfect!
穿上这条裙子，我的新婚之夜一定彻夜难眠
This dress is totally going to get me
laid on my wedding night.
哦，瞧她多幸福啊
oh,look how happy she is.
要知道，我曾以为自己是那种……
You know,I've always thought of myself
as one of those
独立的女人，不会让感情破坏自己的事业
independent women who would never let
any guy mess with my career.
而现在我却真的这么考虑了
And now I'm actually thinking about it.
我感到内疚
I feel guilty,
好像有点太小女人了
like it's un-feminist or something.
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean.
真的？
You do?
我总是把事业放第一感情第二，然而……
I'm always putting my career ahead
of my relationships,and...
说实话，我这样的工作总是带来不少孤独的夜晚
to be honest,there's a lot of lonely
nights in that job description.
瞧，我就是害怕这样
See,that's what I'm afraid of.
选择Ted而不是事业并不是说明你小女人
Choosing Ted over your career doesn't
make you un-feminist.
也许这意味着你们在一起会很幸福
Maybe it just means that you guys would be happy together.
Robin...
我觉得你是最酷的
I think that you are the coolest.
我很高兴我们是朋友
I'm so glad that we're friends.
不可能……
no way......
你才是最酷的
you're the coolest.
不，你才是
No,you are.
好吧，我是
Okay,I am.
我打算留下来
I'm going to stay.
我真是太美了
I am so beautiful!
别告诉我要花多少钱
don't tell me how much it costs.
就这样砍我的头吧
Just snap my neck now,
我就可以死得其美
so I can die this pretty.
你看起来美极了
you look incredible.
好吧，好吧，这要多少钱？
Okay,okay,how much is it,
是“永远不可能”还是“永远永远不可能”？
on a scale of never to never ever?
永远永远永远……
Never ever,ever,ever,ever...
无限时间……
times infinity.
没关系
it's okay.
你知道，新娘之所以漂亮是因为……
You know,what makes a bride beautiful is that
她很开心就要嫁人了
she's just happy to be getting married.
伙计们，我知道我看起来美极了
guys,I know I look amazing,
但重要的是，Marshall和我彼此相爱，对不？
but the important thing is that
Marshall and I love each other,right?
是的，没错
Yes,you're right.
但顺便提一句
But also...
你坐到蛋糕上了
you just sat down in the cake.
没关系，要知道
but,you know what?
很容易洗的，只是些
It's going to come out because it's only...
巧克力和树莓
chocolate and raspberry.
好吧
Okay.
来，站起来，看看有多糟
Come on,get up,let us see how bad it is.
我找到的时候就是这样了
it was like this when I found it?
你打算怎么赔？
And how will you be paying for this?
信用卡……多张
credit card...s.
我想给你……
I wanted to give you... ...
这个
this.
这个才是……
This is what happens when you...
烤熟的成品
you know,let them finish baking.
我想要你留下来
I want you to stay.
我必须去德国
I have to go to Germany.
你要走？
you're going?
是的
Yes.
我必须走
I have to.
你真的这么决定了？
So that's what you decided?
不是……
no......
我本来打算留下来的
I mean,I actually came here tonight leaning toward staying,
可听你说要我留下来
but when you just told me to stay,
让我意识到我必须走
it made me realize that I have to go.
什么意思，今天是反话节？
What is this,opposite day or something?
不是
No.
意思是“是”？
So it is?
Ted，我们才相处两个月
Ted,we've only been dating for two months.
我不能让你为我做决定
I can't let you make this decision for me.
我本来是想让你走的
I was totally going to tell you to go,
然后你又给我这个纸托蛋糕
but then you gave me this cupcake,
让我想起来你有多么好
and it reminded me how great you are.
有没有可能你愿意和我一起去德国？
is there any chance that you would move to Germany with me?
那太疯狂
that's just crazy.
哦，好啊
Oh,okay.
我为你做牺牲就行得通
So it's fine for me to make sacrifices for you,
要你来就太疯狂
but for you it's crazy.
但你留在这还有工作有生活
But you have a job here and a life;
我在那边一无所有
I'd have nothing there.
你还有我啊
You'd have me.
我们才相处两个月
We've only been dating two months.
哦，这不公平
Oh,it's not fair.
我们必须分手，这真不公平
It's not fair that we have to break up.
我恨这样
I hate this.
那么……
So...
我们要分手了？
we're breaking up?
我猜是吧
I guess so.
老天，烂结局，伙计
God,that sucks,man.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
只是压力太大也太早了
It was just too much pressure too soon.
我是说，也许这样想都太疯狂了……
I mean,maybe it was silly to even think...
是的，Marshall,我看见你的新西服了
yes,Marshall,I see your new suit,
棒极了
and it's awesome.
谢谢你的赞许
thank you for acknowledging it.
奇怪，反应这么慢
It was weird that you hadn't.
听着，我明白你们俩最后不得不分手
Look,I understand that you guys had to break up eventually,
但为什么要是今天
but why today?
她明天就要走了
She's leaving tomorrow.
但她还在这儿啊
but she's still in town.
她……
she...
她还在这边
she's still in town.
你们就多相处美好的一天啊
so you spend one more amazing day together.
Ted，这样想
Ted,think about it this way:
要是你知道明天你就要失去你的腿了
If you knew that you were going
to lose your leg tomorrow,
你是坐在沙发上为此哭泣
would you sit on the couch and
cry about it,
还是你会去跑，去跳
or would you run,and jump,
去做一些漂亮的凌空飞踢珍惜你的最后时光？
and do some awesome air kicks while you still could?
漂亮的凌空飞踢？
awesome air kicks?
新的睡裤？
New pajama bottoms?
终于发现了
You know it.
所以我们要么坐在原地哭泣
So we can sit around and cry,
或者我们在腿被砍掉之前去跑，去做一些凌空飞踢
or we can run,and do awesome air kicks before our leg gets chopped off.
等一下，这腿是我们共有的吗？
Wait,so we're sharing the leg?
不，这腿是个比喻
No,the leg is a metaphor.
怎么可能这条腿今天还能做漂亮的凌空飞踢
How could the leg be well enough to
do awesome air kicks one day,
但是却病得不行,必须被砍掉？
and yet still so sick it needs to be
chopped off the next?
我不知道，Ted
I don't know,Ted.
来嘛，我们在一起很开心
Come on,we've had a good run.
为什么以一个吵架作结局？
Why end on a fight?
你想怎么做？
what would you want to do?
我们去完成那些以前谈到过却一直没实现的事情
Let's do all the stuff we talked about
doing and never got around to.
比如去MET？
（大都会艺术博物馆）
Like go to the MET.
我们从布鲁克林大桥上走过去
we'll walk across the Brooklyn Bridge.
看看动物园里的猴子？
See some monkeys at the zoo?
去那个法国-越南式餐厅
我们每次路过都说要试试的
Go to that French-Vietnamese place
we keep passing and say we want to try?
哇，我们最好开始出发吧
Wow,we'd better get going.
漫长的一天
big day.
听我说，孩子们
And,kids,
我们最后一天的确这么过了
that's exactly what we did with our last day.
博物馆，大桥，餐厅
The museum,the bridge,the restaurant,
所有一切美好的事情
and all of those nice things.
Lily，你必须告诉他
Lily,you have to tell him.
那件婚纱可不便宜
That dress cost a fortune.
不，我会等到Marshall什么时候做了错事
No,I'm just gonna wait for the next time
Marshall really screws up,
然后，我在顺便提起来
and then,I'll just slip this in,
这样有了比较就不显得糟
and it won't seem so bad by comparison.
为他背着你偷腥干杯
here's hoping he cheats on you.
但最好只到二垒
but only,like,second base.
瞧瞧我们，两个穿西装的男人
Look at us: Two guys in suits.
感受到空气中的一些刺激感了吗？
You feel that slight tingle?
那是酒吧里的每个姑娘都想要你
That's every girl in the bar wanting you,
而每个男人都想要成为你
and every guy wanting to be you.
事实上，大部分是冲我来的
Actually,it's mostly me,
有些许反弹到你身上
but you're getting some of the splash.
嘿，宝贝
hey,babe.
美元啤酒之夜
Dollar beer night,
所以我炫耀一下,请每个人都喝一杯
so I splurged and got us each our own.
那么，有没有考虑到Barney集团来工作啊？
So,have you thought more about coming to work for Barney corp?
得了吧
please
你的公司才不叫Barney集团
your company is not called Barney corp.
就快了
Yet.
差点儿忘了
I almost forgot.
Sergei把你的帐单给我
Sergei sent me your bill.
B... Barney，这上面说要4000美元
B... Barney,this says $4,000.
我记得你说只要三分之一的价的
I thought you said that it was one-third price.
那可能这是一套1万2的西装吧
must be a $12,000 suit.
看来你必须来我公司了
guess you'll have to come work at my company.
你忽悠我！
You set this up!
这都是你在下圈套！
You set this whole thing up!
我当然……这么做了
I most certainly did...
没用的
it won't work.
就算我去打两份零工
Even if I have to get two extra night jobs,
我也会付这笔帐的
I'll pay your precious tailor.
我不会出卖我的灵魂
I'm not selling my soul.
宝贝，我知道今后会有点困难
Baby,I know that this will make things harder,
但我会做到的，我保证
but I will make it work,I promise.
我毁了一条8000块的婚纱
I destroyed an $8,000 wedding dress.
面试是什么时候？
What time is the interview?
上午9:00，你要准备双新鞋
9:00 A.M.,And you'll need new shoes.
别担心，我认识个人
Don't worry,I know a guy.
我很高兴我们最后一天做了很多漂亮的凌空飞踢
I'm glad we got to spent the day doing awesome air kicks.
我都快厌烦那些性爱了
I was almost too tired for all the sex.
我会想念你的
I'm going to miss you so much.
我也会想你的
I'm going to miss you,too.
嘿，你知道，我是说……要是
Hey,you know,I mean,if,
我回来之后，我们都还单身,我们可以……
when I get back,we're still single,we can...
就算我们不是单身了
even if we're not.
听着，我知道还没一次成功过
look,I know it never works for anyone,but...
……你愿意尝试异地恋吗？
...do you want to try long distance?
当然，当然！
Yes. Yes!
我们可以打破绝对
we can beat the odds.
绝对，去他的绝对
Odds,schmodds.
能成功的
It's gonna work.
我们会坚持下来的
We're going to make it work
这能行
it'll work.
这没成功
It didn't work.
异地恋曾经是……
Long-distance was
现在也是个糟糕的主意
and is a terrible idea,
非常糟糕的主意
a really terrible idea,
太糟糕了
just awful.
不过这都是后话了
But more on that later.
-=cece&飞飞字幕组=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
--------------------------
(*^__^*)cece&飞飞(*^__^*)
-=cece&飞飞字幕组=-
制作: 飞飞
校对: cece
-==用心去经营爱的字幕==-
How.I.Met.Your.Mother
Season 01 Episode 16